http://www.rtwso.org/privacy-policy

Skip to content
RTWSO – Privacy Policy
What is this guide for?Whenever we need to collect any of your data, we will let you know at that point why we need to do so and what it will be used for, but this guide provides a useful overview of all of those situations and provides more detail on how we keep your data secure and up to date, how long we might hold it for, and what your rights are in relation to it.RTWSO is committed to protecting your personal data and will use any personal or sensitive data we collect from you in line with the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR).Who’s responsible for data the group collects?RTWSO is a Data Controller under the GDPR. RTWSO’s Data Protection Officer is the Deputy Chairman who can be contacted at depchairman@rtwso.orgWhat data do we collect and what do we use it for?RTWSO collects data from individuals to help us plan, organise and run its day-to-day operations (e.g. co-ordinating rehearsals or collecting subscription payments) and to promote and market the group’s activities (e.g. marketing mailing lists and photography/video capture).Members: for administering membershipWhen you join RTWSO as a player-member, or during your membership with us, we may need to collect some of the following information on you:
NameEmail addressPhone numberAddressEmergency contact detailsMedical information
Gift Aid DeclarationsAge/genderDBS checksBank detailsPhotos/video footageAudition notes
This data will be used by committee members to manage your membership with RTWSO and to organise and run our activities.If you are a non-playing member (such as a Season Ticket holder, a Patron, a Sponsor, or if in any other capacity we have you on our mailing list), the amount of data we collect may be less than this, of course.If you give us your consent to do so, we may also use your contact details to send you marketing/promotional communications from the group.Any marketing/promotional communication we send you will include a clear option to withdraw your consent (e.g. to ‘opt out’ of future emails) and you can also withdraw consent at any point by contacting the Data Protection Officer.Event attendees: for processing and managing tickets for eventsWhere our events are ticketed, we need to collect data on the person booking (name and email) in order to allow you access to the event and to send you a confirmation of your reservation/purchase. This data will only be used for administering your access to the event/s for which you have booked and will not be used to send you marketing/promotional messages from the group unless you have also provided your consent to receive these (see below).Employees and contractors: for administration and legal/regulatory purposesWe may need (for administration or for legal/regulatory reasons) to collect personal or sensitive data on employees or contractors of the group. Where this is the case, we will explain what this is for at the point of collection.Mailing list subscribers: for marketing and promotionWe offer everybody the opportunity to sign up (consent) to receive marketing and promotional information on the group’s activities (e.g. emails about forthcoming events).When you sign-up to our marketing mailing list we will ask for your name, email, phone number, and address and will use this data to send you information about our events and activities (e.g. forthcoming performances, social events and fundraising events). We may also ask for your preferred topics and communication methods. These allow us to tailor the information we provide to suit your preferences (e.g. email vs post).We will only send you information that is related to the group (e.g. we will not use your data to send you marketing messages from 3rd parties).Anything we send you will include a clear option to withdraw your consent (e.g. to ‘opt out’ of future emails) and you can also do so at any time by contacting the Data Protection Officer.Website visitors: for running and improving our websiteWe may use cookie technology when a person visits our website to collect and analyse anonymised data on how many people have visited, what pages they have looked at and other statistical information. We may also use cookies to allow members to log in and out in order to view our members-only section.You can find out more about cookies at http://www.allaboutcookies.orgDo we share your data with anyone else?We may use third party services to process your data (e.g. Google Drive). We will always make sure any third parties we use are reputable, secure, and process your data in accordance with your rights under GDPR.Are there special measures for children’s data?We do not knowingly collect or store any personal data about children under the age of 13.
How can you update your data?You can contact us at any time to update or correct the data we hold on you.How long we will hold your data?The RTWSO data retention policy is to review all data held on individuals regularly and remove data where we no longer have a legitimate reason to keep it.Where you have withdrawn your consent for us to use your data for a particular purpose (e.g. unsubscribed from a mailing list) we may retain some of your data for up to two years in order to preserve a record of your consent having been withdrawn.What rights do you have?Under the GDPR, you have the following rights over your data and its use:The right to be informed about what data we are collecting on you and how we will use itThe right of access – you can ask to see the data we hold on youThe right to rectification – you can ask that we update or correct your dataThe right to object – you can ask that we stop using your data for a particular purposeThe right to erasure – you can ask us to delete the data we hold on youThe right to restrict processing – you can ask that we temporarily stop using your data while the reasons for its use or accuracy are investigatedThough unlikely to apply to the data we hold and process on you, you also have rights related to portability and automated decision making (including profiling)All requests related to your rights should be made to the Data Protection Officer. We will respond as soon as possible.You can find out more about your rights on the Information Commission’s Office websiteWhat will we do if anything changes?If we make changes to our privacy statements or processes we will post the changes on our website. Where the changes are significant, we may also choose to email individuals affected with the new details. Where required by law, will we ask for your consent to continue processing your data after these changes are made.
Latest TweetsMy Tweets
all content copyright Royal Tunbridge Wells Symphony Orchestra 2020
|
Registered charity No 295781 | privacy policy
The RTWSO reserves the right to change advertised programmes and artists without notice
Orchestra Photos: Denys Clarke Photography
|
Isata Kanneh-Mason Photos: Robin Clewley
Close Menu
